## HR & SAFETY MANAGER

Summary

Human Resources Manager Certified Professional in Human Resources (PHR) Extensive background in human resources management, including experience in workforce planning and employment, human resource development, compensation and benefits, risk management, employee and labor relations, HR technology, global and international HR, talent management. Demonstrated success in negotiating win-win situations, strategic business management, talent management, and change management. HR Skills HR Strategic Planning Training & Development Performance Management Organizational Development Mediation & Advocacy Staff Recruitment & Retention Employee Relations Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) Benefits Administration Project Management Orientation & On-Boarding HR Policies & Procedures Employment Law FMLA/ADA/EEO/WC HRIS Technologies

Experience

HR & Safety Manager

January 2013 to January 2014 Leggett & Platt, Incorporated il/4 Tracy, CA

- Rapidly growing transportation, distribution, and warehousing company Serving the HR and safety needs of the organizations' various
  operations, while leading the change management and cultural transformation efforts to support continued growth and expansion.
- Key Results: Consolidated two small group medical plans with different plan years into a large group plan to maintain the same quality of health plan while saving the organization 75% on the year-over-year premium increase.
- Improved the benefit offerings by adding never before offered dental insurance, voluntary term-life insurance, a vision discount program, employee assistance program (EAP); while expanding the available short-term disability and accident insurance to all of the organizations' associates.
- Streamlined the unemployment and Ohio Bureau of Worker's Compensation (BWC) systems to create consistency and reduce costs.

## Site Supervisor (HR Generalist)

January 2011 to January 2013 ODW Logistics, Inc it/4 City, STATE

- Providing HR support for the operations management team of the company's second largest revenue producing account, while also assisting the organization's staffing firm, and championing special projects for the HR department.
- Key Results:
- Collaborated with the operations management team to recruit, train, and develop a high-performance work team to improve productivity by 70% and reduce turnover by 50% year-to-year, which helped to earn the account the recognition as "Most Improved Account".
- Led the development of a new performance evaluation form and process to improve the processing, tracking, and administration of annual performance reviews and performance management.

Senior Bill Pay Support Associate
January 2008 to January 2011 Fiserv, Inc ï<sup>1</sup>/<sub>4</sub> STATE
Commissioned Officer (NCO)
January 1997 to January 2006 U.S. Army & Army Reserve

- Served in various positions and locations throughout military career.
- Developed human resources responsibilities, including mentoring and counseling personnel, conducting medical and basic skills training and education, managing staff scheduling, and coordinating and documenting treatment.
- Within scope of this responsibility, also directed the personnel operations of 1,000-person medical company, including file documentation, plan monitoring, and processing and training and development documentation.
- Progressively assumed increasing levels of responsibilities, positions, and earned promotions ahead of peers.
- Key Results: Utilized Microsoft Access to automate previously manual documentation processing system for 1,000-person company, resulting in elimination of lost documents, communication breakdown and improved tracking of personnel activity.
- Served as unit Joint Commission and Accreditation of Healthcare Organization inspector and committee representative for an organization earning difficult-to-achieve 100% score on accreditation and maintaining it under 2-year tenure.
- Adapted formal standard operating procedures (SOP) through use of job and task analysis techniques; implemented resulting changes to enable flexibility within diverse environment, resulting in a 30-40% improvement rate and increased operational productivity.
- Received multiple medals of recognition from U.S.
- Army including: 3 Commendation Medals, 2 Army Achievement Medals, 1 Good Conduct Medal and various other decorations.
- Awarded Noncommissioned Officer of the Quarter, 109th Medical Battalion, Third Quarter 2003.

## Education

 $Master\ of\ Science\ (MS): Human\ Resource\ Management\ ,\ 2016\ Keller\ Graduate\ school\ of\ Management\ ,\ Devry\ University\ i'/4\ City\ ,\ State\ Human\ Resource\ Management\ ,$ 

Bachelor of Science (BS): Human Resource Management Franklin University i1/4 City, State Human Resource Management Worked concurrently during college as a Medical Assistant/Phlebotomist and Bill Pay Support Associate. Of Note Professional Affiliations

Certified Logistics Technician (CLT) Instructor, 2013 Certified Logistics Technician (CLT), Manufacturing Standards Skill Council (MSSC), 2012 Career Coach (Franklin University Professional Development Center) 2011 to Present Resume Review Team (Franklin University Professional Development Center) 2011 to Present Training and Development Special Interest Group (T&D SIG) Chair, Human Resources Association of Central Ohio (HRACO) 2011 to 2013 Operational Excellence, Six Sigma Yellow Belt, 2009 Six Sigma 101, 2008 It Happens, Leading Yourself Through Change, 2008 Better Opportunities for Single Soldiers, President, Tripler Regional Medical Command, Hawaii, 1999-2001 Tripler Regional Medical Command, Color Guard, Hawaii, 1999-2001 United States Army Non-Commissioned Officer's Academy,

Primary Leadership Development Course, Schofield Barracks, Hawaii, October 1999 Skills

Army, automate, basic, change management, counseling, documentation, human resources, HR, inspector, insurance, managing, mentoring, Microsoft Access, operations management, performance reviews, performance management, personnel, Phlebotomist, producing, quality, safety, scheduling, SOP, staffing, task analysis, transportation, vision, warehousing